Joel Vinay Kumar

Email: joelvinaykumar.sde@gmail.com https://jvk.netlify.app/ Mobile: 8801156293

I have 3 years of experience in building web and mobile applications. I'm a self-taught engineer and my mission is to solve user problems that add value to their life.

EXPERIENCE

Valuebound Remote

Senior Software Engineer

August 2021 - Present

- Created admin interface including forms to handle special users in mobile app and was responsible for guiding 2 team members
- Refactored e-commerce components in Yojak mobile app to increase code sanity and performance by 40% using best practices and mentored 2 team members
- Promoted as tech lead for a team of 6 developers building ERP based mobile app. Successfully launched it to playstore with 109 users
- Designed, developed and launched the frontend of OKR portal from scratch in 2 weeks with 4 features
- Tech Stack: Express, Node JS, MySQL, React Hooks, React Native, Ant Design, Material UI

Hyderabad Auzmor

Software Engineer

June 2019 - July 2021

- Built API gateway using Express JS middleware, reduced cross-chatter of microservices by 50%, and added protection and rate limits to API groups
- Built an e-commerce module using React JS with Semantic UI for a corporate learning platform catering to a user base of 100K+, currently
- Created a command-line interface using Node JS for displaying the performance of an API with different payload sizes and a variable number of requests per 10 seconds
- Developed responsive and functional user interfaces from Figma designs by integrating them with backend RESTful APIs
- Resolved production bugs with root cause analysis so that they can be handled better in future
- Tech Stack: React JS, Express JS, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB, HTML, CSS

EDUCATION

•	International Institute of Information Technology Hyderabad Master of Science in Information Technology; GPA: 7.9	Gachibowli, Hyderabad July. 2017 – June. 2019
•	St. Martin's Engineering College Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering;	Dhulapally, Hyderabad June. 2012 – July. 2016

Projects

- Simpled (https://simpled-dev.web.app):
 - o A single page twitter like app where you can login through Google and post a text or link as a toot
 - o Technologies used NestJS, Mongoose, Firebase
- Student Mantra- Ed-Tech app(WIP):
 - Developed app for colleges which lets students and college staff to communicate effectively and schedule timetable. noticeboards for different sections of students, receive queries/feedbacks from students, inter-college social media
 - o Technologies used NestJS, MongoDB, React, Docker

HOBBIES

1. Reading books for self help, technology 2. Listening to podcasts 3. Surfing internet 4. Learning new things